ILGWU. Charles Zimmerman Collection of Radical Pamphlets 5780/178
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Frederick Gruin. America's battlefronts; where our fighting forces are, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 65)
- Department of Research and Education, CIO. Guaranteed wages the year round., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 66)
- Communist International Executive Committee. Guide to the XII Plenum E.C.C.I.: material for propagandists, organisers, reporters, training classes., 1932 (Box 5, Folder 67)
- Murray Blyne. Guide to readings on Communism (Box 5, Folder 68)
- Lev Illich Ginzburg. Conditions of labour in the U.S.S.R., 1927 (Box 5, Folder 69)
- Jose Maria Semprun Gurrea. La conscience catholique et les evenements d'Espagne; la question d'Espagne inconnue, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  French
- Sergei Ivanovich Gusev; Earl Browder. Organize mass struggle for social insurance: tasks of the American Communist Party in organizing struggle for social insurance, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 71)
- Francis J. Haas. The American labor movement, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 72)
- Francis J. Haas. Jobs, prices and unions, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 73)
- Francis J. Haas. The wages and hours of American labor, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 74)
- Francis J. Haas. The why and whither of labor unions, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 75)
- Manuel Azana. Habla el Presidente, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 76)
- Mauritz Alfred Hallgren. Why I resigned from the Trotsky Defense Committee, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 77)
- Thomas J. Hamilton; Vera Micheles Dean. Report on the United Nations; A Future for the U.N., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 78)
- Seafarers' International Union of North America. Handbook for permitmen (Box 5, Folder 79)
- Steel Workers Organizing Committee. Handling grievances: a handbook for committeemen of local lodges of S.W.O.C., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  A history of the progress of the union in the Jones & Laughlin Aliquippa Works.
- Earl Parker Hanson. The Amazon: a new frontier?, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 81)
- Eric Hass. John L. Lewis exposed, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 82)
- Harold O. Hatcher. Steel and men, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 83)
- C. A. Hathaway. Collective security the road to peace, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  Radio speech, delivered over CBS, Station WABC, Wednesday, December 22, 1937
- John M. Hayes. Designs for social action, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 85)
- Committee for the Nation's Health. Health needs and what to do about them, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  According to the report of the President's Commission on the Health Needs of the Nation, "Building America's health": Summary
- Fritz. Heckert. What is happening in Germany?, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 87)
- Anders Hedberg; Roy v. Peel: Abner H. Cook. Swedish Consumers in Cooperation, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  Translated by Roy v. Peel and Abner H. Cook
- Eduard Heimann; Reinhold Niebuhr. Liberty through power: a study of the United Nations, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  Forward by Reinhold Niebuhr
- Will Herberg. Bureaucracy and Democracy in Labor Unions, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 90)
- Will Herberg. The C.I.O., labor's new challenge, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 91)
- Here's the answer: fact book on key legislation., 1950 (Box 5, Folder 92)
- Hubert Clinton Herring. Mexico: the making of a nation, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 93)
- Henry Ford; Edward A. Filene; Robert W. Johnson; Matthew Woll. High wages, the basis of recovery, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  Opinions of Henry Ford, Edward A. Filene, Robert W. Johnson [and others] Foreword and open letter by Matthew Woll.
- William A. Higinbotham. Atomic challenge, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 95)
- Sidney Hillman. Reconstruction of Russia and the task of labor, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 96)
- Morris Hillquit. From Marx to Lenin, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 97)
- Lawyers Committee on American Relations with Spain. Hitler over Latin America. Why the embargo against Spain must be lifted now!, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 98)
- Research Department. Hitler terror in 1935 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  With a chapter on fascist terror in Austria.
- Julius Hochman. Labor and the public (Box 5, Folder 100)
- Trades Union Congress. Holidays with pay, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 101)
- John P. Holly. What if they are red?, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 102)
- Nathaniel Honig. The Trade Unions Since the N.R.A., 1934 (Box 5, Folder 103)
- Sidney Hook. Heresy, yes. conspiracy, no!, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 104)
- How much longer will this vilest racketeer of all get away with it?, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  William Randolph Hearst - not a "friend of the people", but a dangerous foe .. not a patriot, but a menace!
- Milton Howard. This 4th of July, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Quincy Howe. Over Here: Who Wants War?, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  v.1:no.1 (1940:April)
- Hubert H. Humphrey. The stranger at our gate: America's immigration policy., 1954 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Jack Huntz. Spotlight on Spain, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Joseph P. Hurley. Papal pronouncements and American foreign policy: a broadcast by Joseph P. Hurley, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Grace Hutchins. Japan's drive for conquest, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- M. N. Roy; Aswani Kurma Sharma. "I accuse!", 1932 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  From the suppressed statement of Manabendra Nath Roy on trial for treason before Sessions court, Cawnpore, India. With an introduction by Aswani Kurma Sharma
- Dolores Ibarruri. Union of all Spaniards, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Complete text of the report to the Plenary Session of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of Spain, at Madrid on May 23rd 1938
- Roger G. Mastrude. If Your Next Neighbors Are Negroes (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Gertrude R. Emery. Industrial home work in Pennsylvania in 1936, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Committee for Industrial Organization. Industrial unionism: the vital problem of organized labor, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Industrial unionist., 1934 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  v.2:no.10 (1934:March)
- Committee for Industrial Organization. Industrial unions mean unity: our answer to president Green, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- IWW (Industrial Workers of the World). Proceedings of the 10th Convention of the Industrial Workers of the World, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- The International class struggle, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  v.1:no.1 (1936:Summer); v.1:no.3 (1937:Spring)
- Educational Department. International Conference on Safety of Life at Sea, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  London-England-Apr. 23-Jun. 10-1948; report to the membership Seafarers International Union.
- Israel's position on the Jordan canal project, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Address by Ambassador Abba Eban before the United Nations Security Council on October 30, 1953.
- It's time to change (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Luigi Antonini. Italian labor today, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Henry Jager. Westbrook Pegler unmasked, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Vasily Jarotsky. The Russian trade unions and the struggle, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- What the enemies of Christian Nationalism stand for: Jew-Communist Internationalism. (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Jewish Labor Committee. Jewish Labor Committee: Aims and Objectives, Organizational Structure, Financial Statement, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Jewish Labor Committee. Jewish Labor Committee: what it does and what it stands for, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- American Jewish Committee. Jews under Soviet rule, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Tom Johnson. The Reds in Dixie: who are the Communists and what do they fight for in the South?, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Willard Johnson. Do you want to be happy and free? (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Joint report of the International Officers to the 35th Constitutional Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  Washington, D.C., Cincinnati, Ohio, October 5th, 1948. President: John L. Lewis.
- James Joll. The Second International,, 1889-1914, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Emanuel M. Josephson. Red record of Adlai Stevenson: "Stalin's choice for President", 1952 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Hays Jones. Seamen and longshoremen under the Red flag, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- William Juhasz. Blueprint for a Red generation: the philosophy, methods, and practices of communist education as imposed on captive Hungary., 1952 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Juni-Aufstand: Dokumente und Berichte uber den Volksaufstand in Ostberlin und in der Sowjetzone., 1953 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Henry Slesser. Justice outlawed; administration of law in German-occupied territories., 1943 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  Foreword by the Right Hon. Sir Henry Slesser
- M. Katz. The assassination of Kirov; proletarian justice versus White-Guard Terror., 1935 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Karl Kautsky; David Shub; Joseph Shaplen; Sidney Hook.. Social democracy versus communism, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  Edited and translated by David Shub & Joseph Shaplen, with an introduction by Sidney Hook.
- Keep America out of War: Unite for Peace, Freedom and Socialism., 1939 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- William C. Kernan. An open letter to Father Coughlin, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Morris Kerstein. Work or war? The president's 1940 budget (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Louis Kirshbaum; Norman Thomas; A. J. Muste; Roger N. Baldwin; Paul H. Douglas; Paul F. Brissenden; David J. Saposs.. Justice for organized workers (Box 6, Folder 40)
  Endorsed by Norman Thomas, A. J. Muste, Roger N. Baldwin, Paul H. Douglas, Paul F. Brissenden, David J. Saposs.
- Vilgelim Germanovich Knorin. Fascism, social-democracy and the communists, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- A. (Aleksandra) Kollontay. The workers opposition in Russia, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Charles Krumbein; Israel Amter. Dollars for democracy (Box 6, Folder 43)
- Bela Kun. The most burning question: unity of action, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 44)
- Philip Kurinsky. Industrial unionism and revolution, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 45)
- O. W. Kuusinen. Prepare for power; the international situation and the tasks of the sections of the Comintern, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 46)
- O. W. Kuusinen. Youth and fascism: the youth movement and the fight against Fascism and the war danger, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 47)
- Labor digest, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  March, 1937
- AFL (American Federation of Labor). Executive Council. Labor and education in 1949: reports of the Executive Council and the annual convention of the American Federation of Labor on education in 1949., 1950 (Box 6, Folder 49)
- Labor and industry in Britain (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Labor leaders betray Tom Mooney: a member of the International Molders Union for 29 years., 1931 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  1st edition
- Workers Education Bureau. Labor's Library: a Bibliography for Trade Unionists, Educators, Writers, Students, Librarians, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Labor and nation, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  v.1:no.1-6 (1945- 1946)
- Alexander Siegfried Lipsett. Labor's partnership in industrial enterprise: a new approach to the investment of union and pension funds, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 54)
- A labor party for the United States, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Herman T. Stichman. Labor's role in shaping home building policy and the future of cooperative housing in America, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  Address by Herman T. Stichman at the Meeting of the Executive Council of the American Federation of Labor, Miami Beach, January 31, 1950.
- Labor says let's go! Roosevelt and Lehman, our two great champions., 1936 (Box 6, Folder 57)
- Labor scholarships abroad: Information on opportunities for Trade Unionists to study in other countries., 1953 (Box 6, Folder 58)
- BLS (Bureau of Labor Statistics). Labor through the century, 1833-1933: an illustrated account, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  Revised edition. Prepared by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the United States Department of Labor for the Century of Progress Exposition, Chicago, 1933, 1934.
- Research Department. Labor under Hitler, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 60)
- Labor unity, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  v.7:no.1-2 (1932:Jan.-Feb.)
- Ernest Bevin; Leon Jouhaux; Matthew Woll. Labor and the world crisis, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 62)
- Labour monthly: a magazine of international labour, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  v.17:no.6 (1935:June)
- Harry Wellington Laidler. America in the depression: supplement of How America lives, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 64)
- Harry Wellington Laidler; Wallace J. Campbell. Consumers' cooperation: a social interpretation, by Harry W. Laidler; The consumers' cooperative movement-a factual survey, by Wallace J. Campbell., 1937 (Box 6, Folder 65)
- Harry Wellington Laidler. Labor governments at work; British, Scandinavian, Australasian., 1948 (Box 6, Folder 66)
- Harry Wellington Laidler. Our changing industrial incentives, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 67)
- Harry Wellington Laidler. Socialism in the United States: a brief history, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 68)
- Lambda; Bertram D. Wolfe. The Truth about the Barcelona events, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  Introduction by Bertram D. Wolfe.
- P. Lang. Peace versus War: The Communist Position., 1936 (Box 6, Folder 70)
- Francisco Largo Caballero. Selected speeches and writings, 1937-1946 (Box 6, Folder 71)
- Eleanor Holgate Lattimore. Labor unions in the Far East, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 72)
- Vladimir Ivanovich Lebedev. The Russian democracy in its struggle against the bolshevist tyranny, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 73)
- Herbert H. Lehman. Freedom and the welfare state, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  Address of Hon. Herbert H. Lehman, on occasion of the 45th Anniversary Luncheon of the League for Industrial Democracy, Hotel Commodore, New York City, April 15, 1950.
- Vladimir Ilich Lenin; Nicolai Lenin. The Dictatorship of the Proletariat and Elections to the Constituent Assembly, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 75)
- Vladimir Ilich Lenin; Nicolai Lenin. "Left" communism; an infantile disorder, by Nicolai Lenin., 1920 (Box 6, Folder 76)
- Vladimir Ilich Lenin; Nicolai Lenin. "Left wing" communism: an infantile disorder, by N. Lenin., 1921 (Box 6, Folder 77)
- Vladimir Ilich Lenin; Nicolai Lenin. The proletarian revolution and Kautsky the renegade, by N. Lenin, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 78)
- Vladimir Ilich Lenin; Nicolai Lenin. The proletarian revolution and Kautsky the renegade, by N. Lenin, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 79)
- Vladimir Ilich Lenin; Nicolai Lenin. Revolutionary lessons: including -- "Towards soviets" "Lessons of the Russian revolution" and "Bourgeois democracy", 1929 (Box 6, Folder 80)
- Vladimir Ilich Lenin; Nicolai Lenin. A new letter to the workers of Europe and America, by Nicholas Lenin., 1919 (Box 6, Folder 81)
- Vladimir Ilich Lenin; Nicolai Lenin. The soviets at work, the international position of the Russian soviet republic and the fundamental problems of the socialist revolution, by Nikolai Lenin, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 82)
- Vladimir Ilich Lenin. Lenin on organization, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 83)
- Vladimir Ilich Lenin; A. Sirnis. The collapse of the Second International, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  Translated by A. Sirnis
- Vladimir Ilich Lenin. Imperialism, the highest stage of capitalism: a popular outline, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Vladimir Ilich Lenin; Nicolai Lenin. Political Parties in Russia, 1917 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- James Lerner. Youth demands peace, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  National Youth Committee
- Max Lerner. The heart of Israel: Histadrut., 1949 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Max Lerner; George Fielding Eliot. World of the great powers, by Max Lerner; Military strength of the big five, by George Fielding Eliot. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Jacob Lestschinsky. Balance sheet of extermination, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Adult Education Program. Let us read: the W.P.A. Adult Education Program of the Board of Education, New York City., 1938 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Alfred Baker Lewis. Liberalism and Sovietism, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- John Llewellyn Lewis. The C.I.O. crusade, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- John Llewellyn Lewis. The future of organized labor, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- John Llewellyn Lewis. Industrial democracy in steel, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Marx Lewis. Max Zaritsky at fifty: The story of an aggressive labor leadership., 1935 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Trygve Lie. The struggle for lasting peace: a record of United Nations achievements, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Rosa Luxemburg. The crisis in the German Social-Democracy, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  The "Junius" pamphlet
- Seafarers' International Union of North America. Listen, Tankerment (Box 7, Folder 15)
- M. M. Litvinov. Czechoslovakia and the world crisis, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- M. M. Litvinov. "Soviet dumping" fable, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  Speech of Soviet commissar of foreign affairs, Litvinov, in European Commission May 18, 1931.
- M. M. Litvinov. The Soviet Union stands for peace, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Local 153 Welfare Fund, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Alain LeRoy Locke. The Negro in America, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- A. Lozovsky; Alexander Bittleman. Lenin the great strategist of the class war, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  Translation and introduction by Alexander Bittleman.
- Jay Lovestone. 1928: the presidential election and the workers (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Jay Lovestone. American Imperialism: The Menace of the Greatest Capitalist World Power, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Jay Lovestone. The American Labor Movement: Its Past, Present and Future. (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Jay Lovestone. New frontiers for labor (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Jay Lovestone. Pages from party history, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Jay Lovestone. The people's front illusion: from "social fascism" to the "people's front", 1937 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Jay Lovestone. Soviet foreign policy and the world revolution, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Jay Lovestone. What next for American labor?, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- A. Lozovsky. The Pan-Pacific Trade Union Conference, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  Hankow, May 20-26, 1927
- A. Lozovsky. What is the Red International of Labour unions? To all workers' delegations taking part in the celebrations of the Tenth Anniversary of the October Revolution, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Rosa Luxemburg. The crisis in the German Social-Democracy, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Rosa Luxemburg. The mass strike: the political party and the trade unions. And, The Junius pamphlet. (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Rosa Luxemburg. Reform or revolution, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  Translated by Integer
- Rosa Luxemburg; Bertram D. Wolfe. The Russian Revolution, and Leninism or Marxism?, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  New introduction by Bertram D. Wolfe
- Eugene Lyons. Everyday life under the Soviet system, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Dwight Macdonald. Fascism and the American scene, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Lois MacDonald; Gladys L. Palmer; Theresa Wolfson.. Labor and the N.R.A., 1934 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Dwight Macdonald; Nancy Mcadonald. The war's greatest scandal! The story of Jim Crow in uniform., 1943 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- A. B. Magil. The people's message to Congress, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 40)
- A. B. Magil. The real Father Coughlin, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- A. B. Magil. The truth about Father Coughlin, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Socialist Party. Manifesto and program of the Left Wing Section Socialist Party, Local Greater New York, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  Issued by Left Wing Section Socialist Party
- Communist Party of the U.S.A. Manual on housing; how to organize a house, the multiple dwelling law, housing crisis in New York city, tenant union organization, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Dmitri Zakharevich Manuilsky. The Communist parties and the crisis of capitalism (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Dmitri Zakharevich Manuilsky. Revolutionary crisis, fascism and war, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Dmitri Zakharevich Manuilsky. The rise of socialism in the Soviet union, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  Report on the results of socialist construction in the U.S.S.R., delivered August 17, 1935
- Dmitri Zakharevich Manuilsky. Social-democracy, stepping-stone to fascism or Otto Bauer's latest discovery, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Vito Marcantonio. The registration of aliens, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  Introduction by Carey McWilliams.
- Vito Marcantonio. We accuse!, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  The story of Tom Mooney
- Benito Marianetti. Hacia una Lucha de Liberation Nacional, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  Spanish. 2nd edition
- Mario Mariani. Matteotti, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 52)
- Harold David Margulies. The worker and the law, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Andre Pierre Marty. For peace! For the defence of the Soviet Union!, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  Abridged
- Karl Marx; Friedrich Engels. The civil war in France, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  Introduction by Friedrich Engels
- Karl Marx; Friedrich Engels; Samuel Moore. Manifesto of the Communist Party, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  Authorized English translation [by Samuel Moore], edited and annotated by Frederick Engels.
- Karl Marx; Eleanor Marx Aveling. Value, price and profit: addressed to working men, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  Edited by his daughter Eleanor Marx Aveling.
- Karl Marx; Friedrich Engels; J. L. Joynes. Wage-Labor and Capital (Box 7, Folder 58)
  Introduction by Friedrich Engels. Translated by J. L. Joynes
- The Marxian., 1919-1921 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  v.1:no.1-2 (1919-1920)
- Marxist quarterly, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  October - December
- Marxist study courses. Course 2, History of the working class. (Box 7, Folder 61)
  Lesson 3-4
- Will Maslow; Joseph B. Robison. Civil rights legislation and the fight for equality, 1862-1952, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 62)
- United Labor Committee of Massachusetts. The Massachusetts story, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 63)
- The massacre of a people: what the democracies can do., 1942 (Box 7, Folder 64)
- J. B. Matthews. Traffic in death: a few facts concerning the international munitions industry, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 65)
- Harry Wellington Laidler. Maximum production: warfare and welfare, symposium, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 66)
- Milton Sanford Mayer. The Dogged retreat of the A.M.A., 1949 (Box 7, Folder 67)
- John McGovern. Terror in Spain, how the Communist International has destroyed working class unity, undermined the fight against Franco, and suppressed the social revolution, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 68)
- R. A. McGowan. New Guilds: a conversation, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 69)
- William J. McSorley. Address delivered by William J. McSorley, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  William J. McSorley, Jr., Assistant Director, Labor's League for Political Education, to the 88th Annual Convention of the New York State Federation of Labor, Hotel Statler, Buffalo, New York, Tuesday morning, June 19, 1951.
- George Meany. Address delivered by George Meany, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  George Meany, Secretary-Treasurer of the American Federation of Labor, to the 88th Annual Convention of the New York State Federation of Labor, Hotel Statler, Buffalo, New York, Tuesday morning, June 20, 1951.
- George Meany. The AF of L case for a just labor law, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  Statement of George Meany, president, American Federation of Labor, on the revision of the Taft-Hartley law, presented before the Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, April 27, 1953.
- George Meany. Our program for social security, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 73)
- afl (American Federation of Labor). Men and women who work (Box 7, Folder 74)
- The menace of a new world war, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 75)
- Shloyme Mendelson. The battle of the Warsaw ghetto, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 76)
- Shloyme Mendelson. The Polish Jews behind the Nazi ghetto walls, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 77)
- Wolf Michal. Youth Marches Towards Socialism, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  Report made Sept. 26, 1935, to the Sixth World Congress of the Young Communist International.
- Miles; H. N. Brailsford; Norman Thomas. Socialism's New Beginning: a Manifesto from Underground Germany, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  Translated from the German "Neu beginnen"; prefaces by H. N. Brailsford and Norman Thomas.
- Spencer Miller. The nineteenth session of the International labor conference, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 80)
- Spencer Miller, Jr.; Ruth Taylor. The pioneer institute of labor, an experiment in understanding, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  A fifteen-year review of Rutgers labor institute against a background of the news, 1931-1945
- Wang Ming; Kang Sin. Revolutionary China today, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 82)